<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alex Kademan</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://alexkademan.site/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://alexkademan.site/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 18:47:21 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 18:47:21 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How I Accidentally Went &quot;Full-Stack&quot;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I began doing web design, Photoshop was still a must-have utility for creating HTML tables. I’ve witnessed the horrors of IE 6, and concocted my fair share of Actionscript monstrosities. All those early projects are now nothing more than learning experiences that just happened to be good enough for the time in which they were written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The things I build nowadays days all involve front end frameworks and back end CMSs of varying size and complexity. I largely prefer to put them together from nothing. I’ve doctored broken MySQL data tables that took days to diagnose. I’ve seen problems with pages not loading properly in other countries that couldn’t be replicated here. And I’ve stayed on top of it all so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did all of it by myself. No team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trouble is that I’m less proud to admit that last fact all the time. I went “Full Stack” not somewhat involuntarily. I just shrugged off the days of being overwhelmed, and figured that it would eventually just work out fine. Over time that meant being busier and busier as I sat at the helm of a growing list of websites, each with their own laundry list of responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I AM proud of the varied accomplishments throughout my career to date, but here in 2016, I just can’t see the advantage to working without a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Full Stack” is a nebulous term to begin with, but I’ve found it to be unhealthy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 15:53:16 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://alexkademan.site/blog/2016/02/13/how-to-burn-out/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alexkademan.site/blog/2016/02/13/how-to-burn-out/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Solful Fitness</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Fitness company website. Extensive use of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mindbodyonline.com/&quot;&gt;MINDBODY API&lt;/a&gt;, allows customers to log in to fitness classes, view their schedule, and find up to the minute information about employees, without leaving the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.facebook.com/&quot;&gt;Facebook SDK&lt;/a&gt; plugin written to display the latest posts from the business.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 15:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://alexkademan.site/blog/2016/02/13/portfolio-solfulfitness/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alexkademan.site/blog/2016/02/13/portfolio-solfulfitness/</guid>
        
        
        <category>websites</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Smart Living Home &amp;amp; Garden</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;E-commerce shop, with custom tailored blogging features. Built using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.x-cart.com/&quot;&gt;X-Cart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 15:49:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://alexkademan.site/blog/2016/02/13/portfolio-smartlivinghg/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alexkademan.site/blog/2016/02/13/portfolio-smartlivinghg/</guid>
        
        
        <category>websites</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pebble Lane Living</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Feature rich e-commerce shop. Patio furniture and outdoor accessories. Built using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.x-cart.com/&quot;&gt;X-Cart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 15:48:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://alexkademan.site/blog/2016/02/13/portfolio-pebblelaneliving/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alexkademan.site/blog/2016/02/13/portfolio-pebblelaneliving/</guid>
        
        
        <category>websites</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
