<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alex Kademan</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://192.168.1.110/~Alex/jekyll/alexkademan.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://192.168.1.110/~Alex/jekyll/alexkademan.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 13:50:51 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 13:50:51 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Build, Learn, Repeat</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently had the (mis)fortnue of building out a handful of WordPress themes. So I’ve been focusing on making a personalized version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Automattic/_s&quot;&gt;underscore&lt;/a&gt; that is suited to the way I like to build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has me looking over how I’ve solved these same problems so many times over the years.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 15:03:16 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://192.168.1.110/~Alex/jekyll/alexkademan.github.io/blog/2016/06/17/build-learn-repeat/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://192.168.1.110/~Alex/jekyll/alexkademan.github.io/blog/2016/06/17/build-learn-repeat/</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When I Accidentally Went &#39;Full-Stack&#39;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The working title of this post was: “How to Burn Out!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been doing web design since a time when Photoshop was a must-have utility for creating HTML tables. I’ve witnessed the horrors of IE 6, and concocted all kinds of spaghetti driven Flash monstrosities that I’d rather not talk about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of that is to say: I’ve always known that my tolerance for pain in the name of my craft is pretty high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actionscript was the first language I learned. Of course I never mastered it. At all. It was a weird way to jump into programming. I know that I’m not the only person out there who was drawn to building websites through Flash, but I know that I could have found a more traditional point of entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came WordPress. Today I am no fan of WordPress. You won’t catch me building things in WP for fun, but I admit that it taught me a great deal about PHP. Fortunately it wasn’t my only teacher. I’ve spent more time with other monolithic PHP applications, and WordPress still puzzles me in terms of some of it’s design decisions under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What came least naturally was Javascript. Despite knowing a few things about Actionscript, Javascript eluded me for a long while. When I finally mastered most of the basics, I was absolutely blindsided by the pace at which Javascript is moving the web forward. Thrilled, but taken aback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days I have a fairly good grasp of all the parts of what makes a website. I’ve managed numerous interrelated domains from the same VPS. I’ve written thousands of lines of CSS both with and without pre-processors. I’ve installed and re-configured SSL certificates, brought websites up to PCI compliance (with MUCH help) and done my share of sifting through error logs for days on end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, now that I look back on how far I’ve come, I would never refer to myself as “Full Stack”. I just wont.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The disciplines that I have forced myself to learn are varied. What keeps a server administrator up at night shouldn’t have to be the concerns of the person who is overseeing the marketing needs, or the look and feel of the site that sits within that server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sure there are superheroes out there who can stay on top of a website’s back-end needs while concurrently implementing a fool-proof UX strategy. I only know that I have tried, and it has taught me a lot about exhaustion.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 15:53:16 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://192.168.1.110/~Alex/jekyll/alexkademan.github.io/blog/2016/02/13/how-to-burn-out/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://192.168.1.110/~Alex/jekyll/alexkademan.github.io/blog/2016/02/13/how-to-burn-out/</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
